You know that feeling when you need to
schedule a meeting, but everything
you need to know is scattered?
I need to schedule a kickoff
for a client's website redesign,
and I want to walk in with a plan.
The client already sent
the pages they want updated.
Their launch date
and a few sites they like.
I'm going to have ChatGPT find that email,
schedule the meeting,
and build a brief to prep me.
Then I'll save the process as a skill
I can use the next time I need it.
I'm using the desktop app here,
but you can also do this in work mode on the web
or mobile at chatgpt.com.
Plugins connect ChatGPT Work
to the apps I already use.
Gmail is already connected,
so ChatGPT  and I'm adding Google Calendar
can find a time and schedule the meeting.
I'll open Plugins, search for Google Calendar,
and select Install.
Then I'll connect my account.
Now, ChatGPT can use my inbox
and my calendar together.
I'll ask ChatGPT
to check for times I'm available
for this specific meeting before Friday.
Looks like it found a few options.
Great.
Now I'll have ChatGPT find the client's email
and use it to draft the meeting invitation.
We'll have it figure out
the right attendees,
a title, and an agenda.
Here's the email,
suggested time, and the meeting invitation.
Everything looks right, so now I'll have
ChatGPT create the calendar event.
The meeting is booked,
but I still need to prep.
for client kickoffs, I like my meeting brief
to cover the objective,
client priorities, decisions,
risks, and next steps.
I'll ask ChatGPT to pull that together
from the email calendar event.
Great.
This is exactly how I like
my meeting briefs.
I have meetings like this often,
and instead of explaining how to do this every time,
I can save it as a skill.
A skill is a reusable set of instructions
ChatGPT can follow whenever I need
the same kind of work done.
I'll call this one meeting prep.
Awesome.
It made the skill, and now I want to make sure
it works the way that I want it to.
I'll run meeting prep on another meeting
and check that it uses the same format
and pulls in the right email context.
All right.
Now the meeting is booked.
The brief is exactly how I like it,
and the next time I need one,
I can run the meeting prep skill.
Booked, briefed,
and ready for the next one.
That's ChatGPT Work.